Hi, I'm Sam Cook, the sales director of
the BC talent team.
So, I think there are likely two
scenarios in that somebody is watching
this video. Um, first off, you've been
contacted by the BC talent team already.
Uh, you're learning about the BC talent
program and you're trying to consider if
switching careers is the right thing to
do.
And you want to know how a career in ERP
could actually be a move into AI.
Or you've made the first step in
acknowledging that the future of work
will involve AI somehow and you're
trying to understand what actual career
opportunities are available to you.
Uh, and to help answer that, I'm
thrilled to be joined by Dona Sarkar.
Dona, let's start with a little bit
about you first.
Um, according to LinkedIn, which is
always a good source of information for
these types of things, you are the chief
troublemaker at Microsoft and you're
running hundreds of co-pilot
experiments.
That sounds rather fun, but what what
does that actually mean?
Hey everyone. Thank you for uh, inviting
me to join you all. So, what it means to
run co-pilot experiments is I work with
companies all over the world to figure
out how they can actually use this AI
thing on their own data, so it's
actually useful and correct. And one of
the things that's been very fascinating
is that
the lack of
I don't want to say the word talent, but
the lack of experience with AI is what
has caused most of the issues at
companies. And it's no one's fault. It's
we suddenly expected everybody in the
tech industry to become an AI expert
overnight. And this is not something
that most people have studied, have
experience in over the past 20 years.
So, what we're seeing is this gap where
people don't know what AI's good for,
what it's not good for. They don't know
how to set up their data correctly, so
AI can use it.
And through experiments by learning how
exactly they can use AI better in their
business.
Cool. And so, what what has your actual
your own journey into an AI-based career
look like?
So, my own journey is actually very
traditional. I did study computer
science back in the day day.
Um, and I've worked in kind of low-level
tech for my entire career. I built
operating systems. I built holograms.
And that was actually where I started
working with AI first because so much of
it is understanding the environment
around us and understanding the human,
how we interact with machines. So,
whether it's gaze, a gesture, voice,
etc. So, my work started with in the AI
space started with all of the various
Azure services that integrated into
Windows to build HoloLens, which was the
mixed reality headset. And then for a
long time, I worked with on the Power
Platform, which is where I got to know
the BC community pretty well. And Power
Platform was actually one of the first
products at Microsoft to get a large
language model running internally.
Amazing. So, I think it's a good example
that like many people
don't like that you start with an AI
career, you you end up there as lots of
people through our program um, will see
and they'll ultimately end up doing,
hopefully.
So, of course, we will uh,
we'll be discussing AI, but in slightly
different context. We'll be discussing
it in the context of ERP, in this case,
Business Central.
AI is is pretty much a household term
now. Everyone's heard of it even if they
didn't want to.
Business Central, an ERP, not so much.
They're certainly not the household
names that you hear all of the time.
In fact, lots of people that we meet,
who to us have really obvious
transferable skills for a career in
Business Central,
they just aren't aware.
Um, how would you describe where BC fits
into the wider Microsoft ecosystem?
So, I think BC is one of the most
special products we have because it
serves a very large audience that is
usually underserved. So, what we call
the SMB market, aka small medium
business. That is 99% of the businesses
in the world, right? Um, most of the
tech industry really serves up
enterprises, which we consider to be,
you know, over
50,000 people.
But, when you look at the medium
business, the small or medium business,
that's anywhere between zero people
50,000 people. That is most of the
businesses in the world. And these are
the businesses because they don't have a
huge number of staff, they need more
tech than anything else. And they need
tech that is fairly straightforward and
um, curated to solve their specific
business issues. So, BC really fulfills
that
that need in the market. And Microsoft
is all in on BC, as you know, we've got
so many events, so much um, churn in the
product itself. And BC was one of the
first Dynamics products to actually get
AI um, activity, right? So, the BC co-
the thing where you upload a picture and
it creates some copy for you, the BC
sales agent. So, BC was one of the first
places in the BizApps world that got
inbox AI and co-pilots integrated into
it. So, BC folks have been aware of it
for, I think, 3 years at that point.
How does that compare to some of the
other Microsoft products? Is is Business
Central further ahead in its capability
or or is it all fairly even?
I think Business Central's right in the
middle.
There's some Microsoft products that are
AI by design, right? You look at
something like
a product called Project Sophia, now
called Business Results Analyst. Or you
look at co-pilot studio or Microsoft 365
co-pilot. These are all AI by design
products that we've invented in the last
3 years. But in terms of products that
have been around a long time and have
adoption, BC is squarely right there.
Um, I always like an enterprise product
that gets, you know, a glow up with AI
because we already have users. We
already have practitioners. We already
have users. And they're the ones who
really understand where the need is,
rather than taking a product that does
not exist. We have no idea who the
customer is, who's the user, who's the
practitioner.
Um, so BC is the kind of product that
does very well in the AI space because
you already got a strong community of
people around it who are ready to go try
all the new functionality and say, this
is good, this is bad, actually give me
this other thing.
Yeah, so on on that functionality, what
what have what would you say the key
differences that you've noticed
in Business Central have been now that
AI is a thing, now that it exists? Um,
how is that compared to Business Central
before AI?
I use Business Central in my personal
life, to be clear, because I run a
retail business out of my house,
actually, which is the chaos behind me.
Um, and one of the most interesting
things is that running a retail business
is annoying because of inventory
management and bringing in new inventory
and offloading inventory. And the BC
co-pilot actually does a lot of this for
you. So, one of the really interesting
things is when I bring on new inventory,
that copy is just generated based on
existing copy I'd already written. And
it just kind of does it automatically. I
don't need to go through a complicated
prompt process. And the first time that
happened, I felt it was a very magical
experience because I had not I forgot
how time-consuming it is to write copy
for each and each and every item that
comes along. Even if it is a copy-paste
modified, that's still time. And the
fact that the BC co-pilot did that for
me since the first day was a very, very
cool experience.
Um, I think one of the things that we
need to do is showcase to people
all of the interesting AI co-piloty
experiences throughout the app that they
might not be even aware of because
there's new things being added all the
time. And every time you look at the app
with new fresh eyes, you're going to
find, oh, there's a new AI thing over
here, there's a co-pilot over there,
there's some automated thing going on in
the background. Um, if you look at the
jobs that exist within Business Central,
um, you think about consultants and
developers, how do you see those two
jobs and their responsibilities changing
due to the AI that exists within the
product?
So, I see these jobs becoming even more
important. Um, the developer job, you
know, fairly predictable. Uh, if folks
who are BC devs, they already know that
they need to get skilled up on AI. There
are some amazing role models in the
community who I look to help guide uh,
the community along. Um, it does take
someone who deeply understands how AI
model works, how to, you know, go and
extend a BC connector with AI or how to
use it in a different context or
whatever it is.
The BC consultant, I think, now has an
opportunity to streamline their work and
say, hey, I'm going to go teach you how
to use BC to your customer and let me
use AI to streamline that process. But
also, how do I go teach the customers
which specific AI
feature would be the right thing for,
say, a retail business compared to a
insurance business compared to, you
know, some other sorts of business.
And I think
what really matters here is the
consultant deeply understands the
customer and their need. And then they
can map it back to the right AI activity
for that customer, rather than just
saying some generic AI thing, right?
Um, so this is where expertise in doing
the job very well for many years is
going to come through because
we have such an opportunity to really
accelerate these small medium
businesses, to give them back so much
time, so they can do more things. They
can actually take their business up
heights that they've not thought of,
right? When we think about business
problems, they're in
they tend to be in three categories.
There's like low ROI, there's high ROI,
and then there's problems we thought we
would never ever be able to solve. The
goal of AI is to be able to go tackle
those problems that we've never been
able to solve, but first we have to get
rid of, you know, the low ROI high high
ROI problems. And then we can clear our
minds and actually go tackle those
so-called impossible problems.
Is there is there a prerequisite skill
set that you think somebody needs to
have to go on and be successful in this
career, especially based on
how you think those jobs will look in
the future. I realize that might differ
from today to
the job of a dev in the future. So, one
of the things I think will be very
important is being able to connect dots.
So, someone has to be able to first ask
good questions because
AI is just asking a series of good
questions. Prompting well, it's having a
decent conversation. It's being able to
say, "I'm asking AI to do this. If it's
not quite right, how do I adjust it?"
So, it's almost being a manager. So,
that's one.
And the other one that's going to be
really interesting is being able to say,
"This AI thing is doing this over here.
I have this problem over there. Can this
AI thing help with that problem?
Or these two AI things are both working
in isolation. How can they work
together?"
So,
the dot connecting activity will become
more and more important. And this is a
skill set that not everyone in the world
has, but is something that we are all
going to have to get better at.
Having a good grounding in BC itself
will be very useful, but being able to
think beyond what is BC do now and
thinking to what could it do just based
on other things in the world will be, I
think, a very good superpower for
people.
Nice. Okay. So, that I suppose ties back
in to what we were talking about earlier
of
you know, there's
there's no natural one way into this
career anymore.
You know, people with lots of different
skill sets, lots of different
backgrounds can all find their way into
a
an AI career
thankfully through us with ERP with
Business Central.
Um, but it's not a one-size-fits-all
into the job anymore. And it's not too
late at all. A lot of people reach out
to me saying, "Oh, if AI feels already
so far along, have I been left behind a
seat?" We are at the Nokia flip phone
era. We are not very far along at all.
We're still doing that thing where when
phones first came out, we would go take
websites and put them on the phone
and make those apps and put a little
scroll bar in.
We're just saving websites as phone
apps. That's what we used to do. We're
doing that with AI now. We are taking
every single product on the planet,
slapping on a chatbot, and calling that
AI.
This is not the end. That's not the end.
This is the very beginning. It's step
one. It's teaching people to prompt
because the AI by design apps are going
to be different and BC's going to evolve
as well, right? We're going to start
seeing changes in apps that come out um
where the UX will be adjusted based on
the interaction that you're having. So,
uploading an item will be a different
experience than
showing someone an item. So, one might
start a gallery, one might start at
upload, right? So, this kind of
adaptive UX will become a lot more
common in the next wave of app dev. And
I think it's really important to
understand like that's how what a human
wants. Human Humans want to receive
value quicker. So, how can we bring in
the value quicker? How can you reduce
the number of clicks they have to do to
get to the thing they're trying to do in
the first place?
If you were about to start a career with
a Business Central partner,
um, what would you be prioritizing now
knowing what you do to to future-proof
your own skill set?
So, what I would do if I was starting
right now and saying, "I'm going to go
focus on BC in a partner." Um, there's
three things that I can that I would
personally do and I recommend everyone
do. The first one is get very familiar
with the BC customer because the BC
customer
they're all very, very different, but go
get familiar with what a small business
looks like and what a medium business
looks like cuz they're not the same as
them.
So, what what tools do they already
have? What problems are they tackling?
Uh, what are some of the unsolved
problems they've got? So, first spend a
lot of time with the customer, get
deeply familiar with that before you go
immediately jump to solution. So, that's
the first part. The second part is get
familiar with BC because it's not the BC
that, you know, 20 years ago debuted.
Um, there's a lot new interesting
functionality, there's a lot more
connectors, a lot more plugins. BC now
connects with Copilot Studio. So, you
can have data in BC and have like some
sort of a chatbot on a website that
pulls from BC data. That's really
interesting. Um, there's lots of
security and concerns and guardrails,
but the BC's connectivity with other
parts of the Microsoft ecosystem, I
think, is really interesting.
And the third part is I would go learn
about AI. I would go figure out like
what is prompt engineering? What What
are AI models? Which are good models?
Which are not good models? How do they
work? How does AI generate generative
AI? How does it actually work under the
covers? How come the results are so
weird and different every time? How can
I normalize them a little bit? How can I
have them be more creative? So, it's
getting one step deeper in the stack,
which I tell everybody to do. In this
moment in tech, we all have to look at
the where we are in the stack and get
one level deeper. And it's going to be a
little uncomfortable and that's a good
thing because that is how we future-prep
ourselves for the career for the next 5
10 years because the thing we have been
doing may work. It may work for a year,
a few years, but at some point this job
is going to evolve, but that's not new.
We had to migrate from BC being the
previous version of 2005 to the version
it is now. So, we've already done this.
We already have the muscle memory. And
now it's time for us to get one level
deeper and really embrace AI as a part
of
something that is native to BC.
I know from many of the talks you've
done, people always leave with some
tasks.
>> Mhm. Uh, what what homework would you
like to give people from from this
conversation? So, the most important
thing all of you should be doing is
going to the BC talent page and clicking
on learn more because we really want
more people to come and join the BC
community because we want you to come
and first have a role in the AI verse.
Make my job easier, folks, because the
number of people reach out to me saying,
"We're looking for AI people. I have
five partners right now in boxing. We
need to hire AI people. Bring us some AI
people." I'm saying, "My friends, I do
not grow them on trees." Okay? I'm
trying to steal from your various
communities and grow them ourselves in
the lab. But what we need you to do is
go to the BC talent page, learn more,
and come and join us, right? Join us to
have a career in the AI verse.